Home Page 1 Nav title: What We Do  

She&rsquo;s 57, and a mother of three. She has hip and back pain, and a bad rotator cuff. She figured she was too out of shape to get in shape.

He&rsquo;s 76. He&rsquo;s got Parkinson&rsquo;s disease, but he&rsquo;s a fighter. He wants to get his motion back&mdash;beginning with a normal walk. 

He&rsquo;s 38. He&rsquo;s been a tennis instructor for 15 years. Then, a knee injury landed him in so much pain he could barely walk. He was headed for surgery. 

What do these three have in common? 

They&rsquo;re all searching for a personal breakthrough in mobility, fitness, and bodily ease. Their issues are too specific or compounded for rote, cookie-cutter moves. They need to rebuild their movement&mdash;from the ground up. 

They found the answer with Dynamic Body Pilates. 

Dynamic Body Pilates is custom Pilates for your body. Influenced by Alexander Technique, FeldenkraisTM,...and dozens of other movement modalities, we create a program specifically for you. We&rsquo;ll teach you where movements should originate from, and introduce you to muscles you didn&rsquo;t know existed, making you more fit and in control.

As your awareness increases, so do your ease and grace. Pain recedes. And you feel like the person you forgot you could be.


The mother of three drastically reduced her pain while getting in the best shape of her life. She recently completed a 17-mile swim in choppy 58-degree water.

The Parkinson&rsquo;s patient walks with control over his movement&mdash;picking up his feet as he goes. 

After two months (8 sessions) sessions with Dynamic Body Pilates, the tennis instructor canceled his surgery. After 4 months (16 sessions) he was back on the court, in full swing.

Contact us to find out how Dynamic Body Pilates can achieve similar results for you. 



Page 2 Nav title: Is This For Me?  

Is Dynamic Body Pilates for me?

Our clients are a broad-ranging group. We train people with a variety of physical and neuromuscular complaints (regardless of degree), people with weight issues, athletes with and without injuries, and others for whom movement is a centerpiece and a source of intrigue and/or challenge.

The one thing all of our clients have in common is their desire to optimize their movement&mdash;for life.  

Dynamic Body Pilates also goes beyond trauma, injury, and pain to fine-tune our clients&rsquo; bodies so that they can prevent future issues. For all of our clients, Dynamic Body Pilates works to discover your body&rsquo;s innate capabilities&mdash;enhancing and unleashing its full range of potential.

We are equipped to address:

Pre Natal * Post Natal * Injury * Trauma * Pain * Multiple Sites of Pain * Postural Issues * Hernias * Arthritis * Carpal Tunnel * Shoulder Issues *Rotator Cuff Issues* Foot and Ankle issues * Plantar Fasciatis * Knee Issues * Back Issues * Hip Issues * Leg Issues * Meniscal Tears * ACL * PCL * Knee and Hip Replacements * Core Strength * Flexibility Issues * ITBand Syndrome * Tendinitis * Scoliosis * Multiple Sclerosis * Herniated Discs * Bursitis * Sciatica * Osteoporosis * Osteopenia * Parkinson&rsquo;s Disease * Obesity * Major Weight Loss through diet or surgery * Pre-Surgery* Post-Surgery * Surgery Avoidance * Post Physical Therapy * Performance Improvement * Mobility Maximization * Injury Prevention & Protection * Fine-Tuning *

Contact us to find out how Dynamic Body Pilates can address these concerns, eliminate pain, and expand your capabilities for the rest of your life.



Page 3 Nav title: Our Services

Dynamic Body Pilates works to discover your body&rsquo;s innate capabilities&mdash;enhancing and unleashing its full range of potential.
If your body is experiencing pain, injury, or trauma, we&rsquo;ll work to liberate your movement and accelerate your recovery.
If your body is fit and strong, our work helps you transcend to the next level.

Our work is 100% customized.  
We study your body: watching you stand, walk, and move. 
We identify your issues, and design a system of exercises that works to: 
Improve coordination, posture, and muscle tone
Release tight muscles and joints, and
Build stability and strength. 
You practice, while we guide your alignment, and help the pieces remain connected to the whole.

We perform our work by appointment&mdash;in 55-minute sessions. In-Home & Office sessions are available in Manhattan and select areas of Brooklyn and Queens. Or, we invite you to visit one of three fully equipped studio locations in Chelsea, the Financial District, and Brooklyn Heights.  

To increase results, all clients are offered practice exercises to perform on their own.  These take minimal time (just five minutes a day) and are extremely rewarding.

In Home & Office Rates
Single Session $140 * Five Sessions $675 ($135 per session) * Ten Sessions $1,300 ($130 per session) * Twenty Sessions $2,500 ($125 per session) * Two Introductory Sessions (for first-time clients)  $190 ($95 per session)  

In Studio Rates
Single Session $115 Five Sessions $550 ($110 per session) * Ten Sessions $1,050 ($105 per session) * Twenty Sessions $2,000 ($100 per session) * Two Introductory Sessions (for first-time clients) $150 ($75 per session)

We honor cancellations given at least 24 hours in advance.
Packages expire one year from purchase.

Contact us for questions and other specifics about our services.
 Page 4 Nav title: Our Founder

About Rebecca Lubart

Founder Rebecca Lubart has been engaged in the art of movement for her entire life. Growing up in New York City, the founder of Dynamic Body Pilates was a competitive figure skater, competing against such greats as Olympian Tara Lapinsky. A student at the prestigious Spence School, she found herself drawn to modern dance, and switched disciplines. She received a four-year Presidential Arts Scholarship (Dance) at The George Washington University, and graduated cum laude with a B.A. in Theatre and Dance.   

Excruciating Pain
At GW, a fall--made worse by poor movement patterns&mdash;led Ms. Lubart to herniate four discs, leaving her in excruciating pain&mdash;at 21. Chiropractors, Massage Therapists, and Physical Therapists alleviated the pain&mdash;but it always returned, more intensely than before.

Seeking answers, Ms. Lubart met a Pilates instructor. She taught her the difference between proper and poor (unsupported) movement. This opened her eyes. Ms. Lubart enrolled in the Kane School of Core Integration, a teacher training and Pilates Certification Program specializing in biomechanically-based Pilates.  

Pain-Free Living
Ms. Lubart turned from intense bodily movement...to intense bodily study. She studied bones, muscles, fascia, and most importantly, how all the different parts of the body should interact to connect as a healthy whole. Through wonderful teachers, training programs, and multiple certifications, Ms. Lubart was able to rehabilitate her own spine. She is able to dance again, and lives a pain-free life.

Ms. Lubart is a certified Pilates Instructor in Mat and Equipment. She revels in introducing others to movement at its absolute finest.

&ldquo;I love the creativity of my job. I see the body clearly&mdash;along with all of its potential, and I love finding the right combination of movements for every person. We can move in so many ways, and none of them have to involve pain, injury, or trauma.&rdquo; –Rebecca Lubart

To see a complete listing of Ms. Lubart&rsquo;s certifications please visit her profile on LinkedIn.
 
Page 5 Nav title: FAQs

Why Pilates?

Q: I&rsquo;ve never even thought of taking Pilates. Why would I? What can it do for me?
Regardless of your current fitness and exertion level, Dynamic Body Pilates maximizes your flexibility, strength, coordination, and agility&mdash;while supporting these wonderful changes (and protecting you) with expert guidance in posture and alignment. We examine the movements you perform every day&mdash;climbing stairs, lifting your child, golfing, dancing, simply sitting at your desk&mdash;and teach you to engage in them with balance and ease. As a result of our work, you&rsquo;ll be leaner, stronger, and more physically capable. Your body will transcend.

Q: I&rsquo;m thinking of taking Pilates classes at my gym. What makes your sessions different?
What makes us different is our creation of a personalized, intelligent program just for you. Each of your sessions is fully optimized with our undivided attention and expert guidance. Rather than restricting you to a set series of generic exercises, we custom design your program to accommodate what you need and want your body to do. We take Pilates principles&mdash;and apply them uniquely to you, your lifestyle, and your life.

What About My Pain?

Q: I have recurring back and hip pain. Should I treat it with Massage, Acupuncture, Chiropractic, or Pilates?
Massage, Acupuncture, and Chiropractic can ease the symptoms of your pain. But they are not ongoing solutions. Without some type of movement training after your treatment(s), you&rsquo;ll probably engage in the same movement patterns that created your pain in the first place. Dynamic Body Pilates is both proactive and preventive: through movement, it aligns your bones and muscles&mdash;to change your body for life.

Q: What makes your one-on-one Pilates instruction different from others?
While resolving her dance injuries, Founder Rebecca Lubart was no less than relentless in her exploration of movement across disciplines and perspectives. As a result, she has an unusually comprehensive understanding of not only physiological cause and effect, but also a vast repertoire of ways to apply her skills to your body. What emerges&mdash;and what you&rsquo;ll experience&mdash;is customization beyond the vast majority of private Pilates sessions: one that is uniquely suited to your physique, concerns, and aims.

Q: Is what you do a type of Physical Therapy?
No. Dynamic Body Pilates is not Physical Therapy. If you&rsquo;ve had surgery, you would typically seek Physical Therapy first, then see us in order to learn how to move well and stay well. If you are considering surgery, the techniques used by Dynamic Body Pilates can help build muscular balance and integration&mdash;and help you steer clear of surgery and Physical Therapy altogether.

One of our clients is a lifetime competitive tennis player and coach. At 38, his knees were badly injured and in pain. He was considering surgery. But after a few months of our instruction, his knees stopped bothering him entirely!  

Q: I want to get in shape and have been thinking of hiring a personal trainer. I'm 57. I&rsquo;ve had two children, foot surgery, and pins put into my knee. I also have arthritis in my hands, bursitis in my elbow, and assorted low back and neck aches. Can Dynamic Body Pilates get me in shape, while addressing all of my issues?
What you need is a safe and strategic plan for exercise, created by someone who understands your body&rsquo;s particular requirements. In short: you need an intelligent person to teach you intelligent exercise. Unlike the vast majority of personal trainers, Rebecca Lubart has studied a broad range of movement modalities and anatomy. In many ways, you are her ideal client: she has helped many clients with multiple body issues to become strong from the inside out. 

Time & Equipment

Q: Can I practice on my own to maximize the benefits of my sessions?
Absolutely. We&rsquo;ll work out a practice plan according to your needs, capabilities, and schedule. Typically, you&rsquo;ll be performing one each of a daily awareness exercise (see the next question), and a brief (5-minute) daily strength exercise that draw from the work of our sessions.   

Q: What&rsquo;s an &ldquo;awareness&rdquo; exercise? How much time do they take?
Awareness exercises take no time. They simply bring consciousness to the ways you move. For example, for someone with hip pain, an awareness exercise might include directing your attention toward: a) whether you propel your legs forward equally as you walk, and b) whether your feet face the same direction as you walk. The &ldquo;work&rdquo; is easy: it takes seconds, and is extremely rewarding.   

Q: Is the work the same regardless of whether I come to your studio or work from home?
All of our three studios are equipped with a Pilates Reformer and Cadillac among other machines. But you don&rsquo;t need this specialized equipment to perform Dynamic Body Pilates. Our sessions can be conducted with props, such as a foam roller and small weights…or without anything at all.   A few of our clients own a Pilates Reformer system. If you wish to purchase one, they range from $1,600 to $6,000, and you can find them on sites such as www.pilates.com (please consult your instructor first). But again: a Reformer is not required to perform our work.
